Guide to the William Rainey Harper Papers 1872-1938
University of Chicago Library
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries 1: General
    - Correspondence, April 21 - June 6, 1904, Ball, S.F. Davidson, Rev. R.B. Dewey Elliott, A.J. Hale, W.G. Hyde, Dr. James N. Jesse, Pres. Jordan, Herbert R. Levering, Rev. F.H. McClure, Thomas D. Morris, Samuel T. Nichols, F.D. Ruggles, F.D. Sedgwick, Dr. William Stiles, Rev. D.M. Thwing, Pres. Charles F. Van Hise, Charles R. Von Holst, Mary Van Osdel, Rev. O.W. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, June 7 - August 30, 1904, Baker, A.L. Ball, S.F. Barrows, Mary E. Chandler, H.P., Secretary for Harper Comstock. G.C. Gilman, D.C. Hall, Rev. C.C. Harper, Samuel (father) Harper's Weekly, Editor Hektoen, Ludwig Hitchcock, Mrs. Annie Hulley, Lincoln Lathrop, Bryan Mechem Morris, Rev. S.T. Sisson, E.O. Smith, Mr. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, August 3 - 30, 1904, Gunderson, H. Harper Harper's Weekly, Editor Hulbert, E. McFarland, A.C. Ridgway, E.J. unidentified (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, September 3 - October 17, 1904, Bailley, O. J. Bloom, Bell Brown, W.H. Chander, Cortelyou, Hon. Geo. B. Deneen, Charles H. Garfield, Hon. James R. Hulley, Pres. Lincoln July, J.L. Kent, Mrs. William Lagergren, Siegrid MacLean Ridgway Rubinkam, Nathaniel I. Smith, George Adam Stagg Symmes, Frances Newton Van Hise, Pres. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, October17 - November 15, 1904, Cross, George Cummings, John Dodson, Dr. John M. Foreman, Henry G. July, J.L. Mandel, Leon Parker, F.W. Senn, Dr. Slocum, Pres. Swanson, C.O. for the Marshall Field and Co. Law Dept. Symmes, Frances Wilson, Thomas, M. Wormser, Leo F. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, November 17 - 30, 1904, Billings, Dr. Brundage, Edw. J. Cobb, Miss Cross, Geo. Foreman, H.G. Hack, Mrs. F.C. Harper's list of appointments for Nov.22 Howe, E. Kohlsaat, H.H. Myers, Johnston Ransom, J.C. Rockefeller, Laura S. Rosenwald, Julius Smith, G.B. Smith, Geo. Adam Stagg Taft, W.H. Wallace, Miss (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, December 1 - 31, 1904, Brown, C.R. Brown, Glenn Chandler, Mr. Foreman, H.G. Freeman, Helen Alden Gilbert, Simeon Hammond, R.R. Hirsch, Dr. Hopkins, Hon. A.J. Hurlbut, Jesse L. Hutchinson, Frances K. Johnson, Herrick Jones, Lester Mann, James R. McCleary, Rep. James T. Parker, Dr. A.K. Stewart, Graeme Webster, R.W. Willmening, F. A. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, January 1 -- 31, 1905, Butler, Nathaniel Chandler, Henry Porter Charles Scribners Sons Cobb, William H. Fay, C.N. Felton, S.M. Ferson, Earl Bixby Frost, Mary Hazard Gunsaulus, F. W. Hammond, R.R. Harper and Bros. Hurlbut, Dr. Jesse L. Job, F.W. Johnson, Franklin Jones, Lester B. Judson, Edward Levering, Eugene Nelson, Roy Bachelder President of the U.S. Tarbell, Mr. Tolman, A.H. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, February 1 - 8, 1905, Burton Crandall, Rev. L.A. Edwards, G.D. Fiske, A.A. Fuller, Nellie E. Hirsch, Dr. Holt, Charles S. Huston, C.A. Hutchinson, C.H. Hyde, Pres. Wm. DeWitt Jordan, E.J. Judson, Dr. Edward Kraft, Homer, Sec. The World Today Lytton, Henry C. Marvin, S.W. of Charles Scribner's Sons Nelson, R.B. New York Evening Post, Editor Schlesinger, Leopold Vincent, John H. Wheeler, Rev. Kittredge (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, February 8 - 15, 1905, Baldwin, Dr. A.E. Bitting, W.C. Blatchford, Mary E. and E.W. Brown, of Newton Theological Seminary Burton, E.D. Buttrick, Wallace Crandall, Lathan A. Edwards, Rev. G.D. Favill, Dr. Henry Baird Ferson Foster, George B. Gurney, Frederick J. Kern Paul V. Klenze, Camillo von Kraft, H.L., The World Today Laughlin, J.L. McClintock Taylor, Graham Van Hise, Pres. Vincent Wheeler, Rev. Kettredge Willett, Herbert L. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, February 15 - 17, 1905, Brown Buck, Carl D. Burton Butler, Nathaniel Carman, Geo. N. Dougherty, N.C. Henderson, Charles James, Edmund J. Jewett, Prof. Johnson, Mrs. J.C. Kern, Prof. Paul Kirkland, James H. Klenze, Prof. von MacLean, M.H. Remsen, Prof. Schmidt-Wartenberg, Prof. H. Smith, Gerald B. Soares, T.G. Vincent, Bishop West, Andrew F. Whitman, Pres. B.L. Whitman, Prof. Willett (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, February 17 - 20, 1905, Bartlett, A.C. Beard, Mr. and Mrs. Frank Breasted Burwell, Leslie M. Coulter, John M. Dewhurst, Frederic E. Dickerson, Emma R. Eckels, Pres. M.H. Faunce, W.H.P. Flint, Mrs. Freeman, Justice Henry V. Glessner, J.J. Hall, G. Stanley Hardy, Ruth Harper, R.F. Hilprecht, N. H. (?) Hirsch, Emil G. Johnson, Herrick Jordan, David Starr Kato, Akizane MacLean, M.H. McClenahad, David A. Meredith, E.B. Merrill and Burnham Morehouse, H.L. Ramsey, F.H. Simpson, G.B. Sternberg, Washington Stone, Maudie L. Tarbell, Prof. Universal Exposition Walker, Geo. C. Wever [?], Consul Wheeler, Benjamin Ide (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, February 20 - 21, 1905, Bailey, O.J. Bancroft, Edgar A. Barrows, Mrs. John Henry Beard, Gerald H. Burgess, T.C. Burnham, Prof. Sylvester Butler, Nicholas Murray Chamberlain, Georgia Coe, Prof. Geo. A. Collie, Dean G.L. Curtis, Prof. Edward L. Halgate, Thomas F. Hamill, Pres. E.A. Kimball, Kate F. Low, Seth Mann, Hon. James K. Mathews, Shailer McCormick, Alexander McKibben, Prof. Geo. F. Meyer, Gustave Schurman, J.G. Walker, George C. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, February 21 - 28, 1905, Alderman, Edwin A. Beck, Carl Butler, Nicholas Murray Chandler Dods, Marcus Field, Wm. A. Gilcrist, F.H. Higinbotham, H.N. Hopkins, A.S. Jesse, Pres. Johnson, Dr. Herrick Ladd, George Trumbull Lyon, Elias P., A.C. Eycleshymer, C. Hugh Neilson, and Orville H. Brown Northrup, Mrs. Herbert F. Phelps, Arthur S. Small Smallwood, John J. The Sisters of St. Dominic Thorp, Willard B. Walker, Geo. C. West, Andrew F. (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, March 1 - 8, 1905, Bartlett, A.C. Cooley, Edwin G. Curtis, Edward L. Droppers, Pres. Garrett Faye, Charles M. Finley, Pres. George, Pres. James H. Godbey, C.H. Goodspeed, Mrs. Gunsaulus, Dr. Hale [?] Higinbotham, H.N. Hopkins, Seantor A.J. Hoyt, Wayland Hutchinson, C.L. Jesse, Pres. Judson MacArthur, R.S. McDowell, William Fraser Shepardson Smith, Geo. Adam Swedish and Dano-Norwegian Seminaries, faculty and students Walker, Geo. C. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, March 9 - 17, 1905, Bartlett, Florence Dibell Bestor, Arthur E. Brown, Caroline M. Brown, Charles Rufus Colwell, R.S. Dods, Marcus Fraser, W..J Hall, George W. Hamilton, D.G. Hulbert, E.B. Johsnson, Franklin W. Jones, Lester B. Lee, Rev. S.H. Matz, Miss Evelyn Salisbury Smith, Preserved Van Hise, Pres. Van Osdel, O.W. Wilson, Walter H. Wrenn, John H. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, March 17 - 31, 1905, Abbott, Frank Frost Aderman, Pres. E.A. Barbour, H.H. Brown, Charles Rufus Capps, Edward Chamberlain, Harrie R. Fraser, W.J. Godbey A.H. Harper, Mrs. Heckman, Mr. Holland, W.J. Hulley, Pres. Lincoln Judson McKenzie, W. Douglas Sanders, Frank K. Walker, Geo. C. Watson, Charles A. Wheeler, Kittredge Wood, Nathan E. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, March 29 - April 24, 1905, Baker, Pres. James H. Barbour, Rev. H.H. Behan, Warren P. Bennett, Mrs. Philo A. Blackburn, Alexander Curtis, Edward L. Faithorn, Pres. J.M. Felton, Pres. S.N. Fields, W.A. Godbey, Allen H. Gunsalulus, Dr. Hammond, R.R. Hutchinson, C. S. Johnson, Mr. Judson, H. P. Miller, Mr. Nuss-Arnolt, W. Sisson, Edward O. Wallace, Elizabeth Watson, C.A. unidentified (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, April 24 - May 17, 1905, Barbour, Rev. H.H. Brown, Charles Rufus Cobb, Rena Faithorn, Pres. J.N. Felton, Pres. S.M. Harper, Samuel (father) Johnson, Chaplain P.C. McKibben, Prof. G.F. Miles, C. Morton, Dr. Sherer, A.W. Smith, George Adam St. Clair, Robert Van Dyke, Henry (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, May 17 - June 1, 1905, Aldrich Beckley, Rev. John T. Bendler, Aug. C. Cameron, J.H. Deeks, W.E. Foster, G.B. Harper, Lyle Harper, Samuel (son) Judson Mason, Geo. L. McKibben, Miss Ruth Sisson, E.O. Smith, Geo. Adam Watson, John B. Whited, O.O. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, June 1 - July 12, 1905, Bendler, Rev. A.C. Carroll, Willie Godbey, A.H. Goldthwaite, Nellie E. Harper, Samuel (son) Hewes, Amy Jesse, Prof. Jesse, R.H. Judson, Edward Kraft, Homer L. Lawrence, Rev. W.M. Levering, Eugene McClenahan, D.A. McLeish, Bruce Toffteen, O.A. Vincent, George E. Watson, John B. Wited, O.O. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, July 13 - 24, 1905, Brown, R.B. Buttrick, Wallace Greet, Ben Hall, Frank H. Harper, Floyd E. Harper, Samuel (Son) Jordan, Mrs. Sue Smith Keen, George Lacklen, Mary L. McClenahan, D.A. Salisbury, Mr. Shepardson, F.W. Sparks, Mr. Vincent, Geo. E. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, July 25 - August 18, 1905, Buttrick, W. Chandler Clanton, S.T. Corwin, Miss Coulter, J.M. Crane, Mrs. Elizabeth Downie, Rev. Joseph Harper, Samuel (Son) Harper, Sue Smith Manly, JM Michelson, Edna S. Rainsford, W.S. Singer, Isadore Sparks, E.E. Spelman, Lucy Tarbell, F.B. Torrey, Charles C Vincent. Geo. E. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, August 19 - 31, 1905, Gunsaulus Harper, Samuel (son) Jones, Lester Judd, George Judson, Edward Kellogg, J.H. Roosevelt, Theodore Small, A.W. Spelman, Miss Lucy Tarbell Wilson, Thomas M. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, September 2 - 23, 1905, Brotherhood of St. Andrew, President Burton, E.D. Coulter, John M. Faunce, Pres. W.H.P. Gardner, Robert H. Hamilton, W.H. Herrick, Robert James, Pres. Edmund J. Justin, Ernest L. Locke, George H. Mansfiled, Richard McKenzie, Spencer G. McKibben, George F. Miller, Newman Wallace, Elizabeth White, John T. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, September 28 - October 14, 1905, Bartlett, W. A. Burton, E.D., A.G. Lester, and F.W. Shepardson Chamberlain, Georgia Elliot, W. A. Gunsaulus Hale, William Gardner Hall, James Parker Harper, Ellen Elizabeth (mother) Harris, NW Haupt, Prof. Paul Hulbert, Eri B. James, Pres. (of Univ. of Illinois) Jameson, J.F. Jusserand Mansfield, Richard Mathews Price, SE, WA Elliot, and PW Crannell Pritchett, Pres. Henry S. Rowley, Francis H. Smith, Mary L.G. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, October 14 - 31, 1905, Armour, George A. Arnoldson, Torild Barnes, Rev. L.C. Bitting, Rev. W.C. Burton Buttrick, Wallace David, Henri C.E. Goode, Paul Judson Price, Ira M. Price, SE Raycroft Sanders, Frank K. Small, Charles P. Smith, Mrs. Steele, CM Stetson, H.L. Stevens, Prof. G.B. Ten Broeke, James Twitchell, Rev. JH (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, November 1 - 16, 1905, Buttrick, Wallace Dougherty, Ralph L. Fleming, Miss Gaskell, S. C. Gordon, Dr. John Hall, Dr. Charles Cuthbert Harrison, Charles C. Kellogg, Frank B. Kelly, Pres. Robt. L. McLeish, Andrew Moxon, Philip S. Reynolds, James B. Robinson, Mrs. Harriet P. Sanders, F.K. Schauffler, Dr. W.G. Schauffler, M.G. Thoms, Edith M. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, November 16 - December 12, 1905, Bradley, Lydia Brown, W.C. Carpenter, F.I. Chamberlain, Miss Committee of One Hundred Cook, J.E. Crandall, Lathan A. David, Henri C.E. Dennan, J.G. Evans, Milton G. Freeman, Henry V. Freeman, Justice Gardner, Ida M. Gates, F. S. Gunsaulus, Dr. Hall, G. Stanley Harlan, Pres. Richard D. Hirsch, Dr. E.G. Hutchinson, Mrs. C.L. Kellogg, Frank B. Moore, Eliakin H. Park, R.E. (Jr.) Shepardson Thwing, Charles F. unidentified (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, December 12 - 30, 1905, Blatchford, E. W. Capps, Rhoda Jeanette Evans, Professor Milton G. Harper Heckman Hitchcok House, members Hutchinson, C.L. Judson, H. P. McDowell, Bishop William F. Park, R.E. Shepardson Simpson, Walter Harper Stoutmeyer, J.H. Zeublin (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, January 1 - February 17, 1906, Bitting, W.C. Brown, Charles Rufus Donnelley, T.E. Eldredge, William A. Hyde, James Nevens Judson, H.P. Jusserand, M. Sisson, E.O. Wilson, Woodrow (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, n.d., Ash, L.A. Ashlimase, Lorley Ada Buttrick Chamberlain, Geo. Chandler, H.P. Henderson, Charles R. Laughlin, J.L. Rogers, Jas. Gamble Small, Albion W. Troop, J. Carter (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 2: Distinguished Persons
    - Correspondence, Letters of Distinguished Persons (copies) (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1888-1889 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1894-1895 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1897-1898 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1899-1901 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1902 - 1903 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1904 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Gates-Harper Correspondence, 1905 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Goodspeed-Harper Correspondence, 1887-1892 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Goodspeed-Harper Correspondence, 1889 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Goodspeed-Harper Correspondence, 1890 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Goodspeed-Harper Correspondence, 1891-1902 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Goodspeed-Harper Correspondence, 1903-1905 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1891- 1892 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1895 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1896 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1897 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1898-1899 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1900-1901 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1902 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1904 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1905 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Judson-Harper Correspondence, 1905 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 3: Family
    - Harper Family and Family Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Harper Personal Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 1a)
  - Subseries 4: Publishers
    - Harper Correspondence with Publishers (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Harper Correspondence with Publishers (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Harper Correspondence with Publishers (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 5: Academic
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, 1886 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, January 1887 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, February 1887 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, March 1887 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, April 1887 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, May-June, 1887 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, July 1887 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, August 1887 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, September 1-7, 1887 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, September 8-16, 1887 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, Sept. 17-22, 1887 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, Sept 23-30, 1887 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, October 1-11, 1887 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, October 12-31, 1887 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, March 1888 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, April 1888 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, October 1888 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, November 1888 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Harper "Old Testament Student" Correspondence, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - School of Hebrew, Correspondence,. Harper's corrections of lessons of Rev. Daniel Seymour, 1883-1886 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - School of Hebrew, Correspondence,. Harper's corrections of lessons of Rev. Daniel Seymour, 1883-1886 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - School of Hebrew, Correspondence,. Harper's corrections of lessons of Rev. Daniel Seymour, 1883-1886 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 6: Founding of University of Chicago
    - Miscellaneous letters concerning the founding of the University (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Advocates of Harper's refusing the Presidency (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Advocates of Harper's accepting the Presidency (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Harper's formal acceptance of the Presidency, February 16, 1891 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Harper's possible successors (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Colleagues from Yale (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 7: Early appointments
    - Abbott, Frank F. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Adams, H.B. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Angell, James R. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Barnard, E.E. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Barnes, C.W. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Bauer, G. (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Bayley, W.S. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Bastin, Edwin S. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Bemis, Edward W. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Schulze-Berge, F. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Bergeron, E. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Bickmore, Albert S. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Bierworth (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Birmingham, T. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Blackburn, F.A. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Boise, J.R. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Boyd, James H. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Bronson, S. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Brownson, C.L. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Bruner, J.D. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Buck, Carl (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Buckingham, Mary (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Bulkley, Julia (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Burks, J. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Burton, Ernest D. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Butler, Nathaniel (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Butterworth, Hoarce (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Chandler, Cha. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Clark, S.H. (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Coulter, John M. (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Crow, Martha (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Cutting, Starr W. (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Dewey, John (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Dike (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Ely, Richard J. (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Foster, Alice B. (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Freeman, J.C. (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Gedde (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Gile, M.C. (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Goodspeed, G. (and von Holst) (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Grose, Howard B. (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Growth, Peter (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Hale, George E. (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Hale, W.G. (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Hancock (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Henderson, C.R. (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Henderson, George (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Hendrickson, George (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Herrick, C.L. (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Huling, Ray G. (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Hyde, Douglas (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - James, Edmund J. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Judson, H.P. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Knapp, W. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Lauder, W. Waugh (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Lawrence, T.J. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Lawton, W.C. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Lengfeldt,m Felix (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Mace, W.H. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Manly, John H. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Maschke, H. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - McClintock, W.D. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Michelson, Albert A. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Miller, A.C. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Moncrief, J.W. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Moore, E.H. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Moulton, R.G. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Nef, John U. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Nordell, Philip A. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Northrup, G.W. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Palmer, G.H. (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Pietsch, Karl (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Price, Ira M. (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Reynolds, U. (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Robertson, Luanna (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Robinson, E.G. (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Root, T.H. (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Rowland (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Salisbury, Rollin D. (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Sanders, Frank (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Schevell, Ferdinand (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Schneider, E.A. (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - See, T.J.J. (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Selian, A.B. (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Shorey, Paul (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Shepardson, F.W. (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Simpson (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Slaught, H.E. (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Stagg, A. (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Starr, Frederick (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Stieglitz, Julius (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Strong, Chas. A. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Small, Albion (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Smith Justin A. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Stratton, Samuel (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Talbot, Marion (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Tarbell, F.B. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Terry, Benjamin (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Thatcher, Oliver J. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Thomas, Colvin (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Tolman (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Tufts, Jas. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Veblen, T.B. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Von Holst, Edouard (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Wadsworth, F.L.O. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Wergeland, Agnes (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Whitman, C.O. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Wilder (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Wilkinson, W.C. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Williams, Wardner (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Wood, Irving (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Wright, G.H. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Young, J.W.A. (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Zeublin, Charles (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Subseries 8: Harper-Shepardson Business
    - 1900-1903 (Volume 1)
    - 1902-1904 (Volume 2)
- Series II: Speeches and Manuscripts
  - Address to first Convocation (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - The President's Quarterly Statement on the Condition of the University for the Spring Quarter 1896" 28 p, printed with handwritten corrections. (See University Record, Vol. I, 1896-1897, p. 224-228 for published version.) (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Lecture notes, "Art Among the Hebrews" (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Lecture notes, "The Bible and the Monuments" (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Lecture notes, "Prophecies Connected with the Fall of Jerusalem I" (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Lecture notes, "Prophecies Connected with the Fall of Jerusalem II" (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Lecture notes, "Prophecies Connected with the Fall of Jerusalem III" (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Lecture notes, "Prophecies Connected with the Fall of Jerusalem IV" (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Lecture notes, "Prophecies Connected with the Fall of Jerusalem V" (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Lecture notes, "Prophecies Connected with the Fall of Jerusalem VI" (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Lecture notes, "Prophecies Connected with the Fall of Jerusalem VII" (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Lecture notes, "The Prophetic Element in the Old Testament as Related to Christianity" (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Lecture notes, [untitled lecture concerning customs of the Jews] (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Series III: Personal
  - Correspondence, with Dr. Billings concerning Harper's illness (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, with Dr. J.H. Kellogg concerning Harper's illness (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Harper's last operation (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Harper's funeral and memorial services, including an outline of the funeral (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, A (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, B (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, C (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, D (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, E-F (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, G (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, H (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, I-J (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, K (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, L (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, Mc (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, M (Box 16, Folder 9)